Vivaldi Browser privacy policy
==============================

We do our utmost to protect the security of personal information for users of Vivaldi. Find our full browser privacy policy here.

### Vivaldi Browser privacy policy

At Vivaldi Technologies AS (“Vivaldi AS”), protecting your privacy is a top priority. We strictly protect the security of any and all personal information you provide to us while using Vivaldi products and services. We do not share or sell information to any third party and we proactively protect all user data from disclosure, with the only exception being if requested by legitimate law agencies with a court order.

### Type and purpose of data collected by Vivaldi AS

When you install Vivaldi browser (“Vivaldi”), each installation profile is assigned a unique user ID that is stored on your computer. Vivaldi will send a message using HTTPS directly to our servers located in Iceland every 24 hours containing this ID, version, cpu architecture, screen resolution and time since last message. We anonymize the IP address of Vivaldi users by removing the last octet of the IP address from your Vivaldi client then we store the resolved approximate location after using a local geoip lookup. The purpose of this collection is to determine the total number of active users and their geographical distribution.

Vivaldi includes various links to websites in the browser default bookmarks. Some of those websites are partners of Vivaldi AS and some are not. Vivaldi AS receives shared revenue from those bookmark partners. That’s how we are able to provide this software free of charge to our users and continue to stay awesome! We work to only include bookmarks that are valuable to our users regardless of whether we receive any revenue or not. Some of these content providers set cookies on their websites (as mentioned below). You are, of course, free to remove any or all of the bookmarks, if you prefer.

Your browsing history such as visited URLs, typed search keywords and downloaded content are stored in your client profile and only accessible by your own action. Vivaldi AS has no access to this data. Your history cannot be shared unless it is by your own action.

Vivaldi features a built-in password manager, which stores your login credentials for sites where you’ve enabled this feature by selecting to store your credentials in Vivaldi’s password manager. Vivaldi uses password storage frameworks provided by the operating system on your computer device and your data is encrypted if encryption is supported by the framework.

If you use Vivaldi Sync feature, the documentation about the data we collect and for what purposes for this service is available [here](https://vivaldi.com/privacy/sync/).

If you turn on automated crash log sharing in settings, Vivaldi will send a detailed log to our server when it crashes. Crash logs may contain personal data that resides in relevant sections of your computer’s memory, including passwords and chunks of content from the webpages you visit. This data is however never made available to any of our staff as we immediately process the received data to extract a mere stack trace, which gives us an idea about where in Vivaldi the crash occurred. Once this process is complete, the full log is removed from our services and we only retain, for 60 days, the stack trace and the URL of the page that was active at the time of the crash.

To determine the availability of the Direct match sponsorship in your country, Vivaldi AS uses a local GeoIP database to determine your country, based on your IP address. This is only done if Direct match is used, and the IP address is discarded immediately.

### Type and purpose of data collected by third party vendors

When you turn on Search suggestions in your Settings (Settings > Search), Vivaldi will send a request to the chosen search engine with the typed keyword in order to display search results. Privacy policies for individual supported search engines can be found [here](https://vivaldi.com/privacy/browser-3rd-parties/).

On desktop and Android, Vivaldi integrates the [Safe browsing API from Google](https://developers.google.com/safe-browsing/), which checks the site you are visiting against a master list of known suspected phishing and malware sites. On desktop, this feature can be turned off in the Privacy settings (Settings > Privacy > Privacy).

We use Google’s form autofill feature that helps you fill out forms on the web more quickly. Autofill is enabled by default and in the desktop browser, it can be turned off at any time in Vivaldi’s settings. This feature does not send your personal information to Google. Detailed information of what is shared can be found [here](https://www.google.com/chrome/privacy/whitepaper.html#autofill).

Many websites use cookies to identify repeat visitors and store information about their site visitors. Vivaldi stores cookies based on the user’s privacy settings (Setting > Privacy > Cookies) but how the cookie is used is determined by the website you are visiting and types of cookies. Therefore it is important that you understand the privacy policy of the websites you are visiting. You can view, manage and remove all stored cookies in your privacy settings.

In case you set up Vivaldi Mail or Calendar to access your Gmail or Google Calendar, Vivaldi’s use of information received from Google APIs will adhere to the [Google API Services User Data Policy](https://developers.google.com/terms/api-services-user-data-policy#additional_requirements_for_specific_api_scopes), including the Limited Use Requirements.

Last modified and effective: December 15, 2023.

* Browser
* Community
* Websites

**Browser**

**Features**

**Mail**

**News**

**Community**

**Help**

**Press & Media**

**About**

AfrikaansAzərbaycancaбългарскиCatalàČeštinaDanskDeutschEnglishEspañolفارسیSuomiFrançaisGalegoMagyarIndonesiaÍslenskaItaliano日本語関西弁TaqbaylitKurdish한국어NederlandsNorsk bokmålpolskiPortuguês (Brasil)Português (Europeu)РусскийSlovenčinaSlovenščinaСрпскиSrpskiSvenskaTürkçeUkrainian简体中文繁體中文

© Vivaldi Technologies™ — All rights reserved. | [Status](https://vivaldistatus.com/)
